An eclipse awakens an ancient monster whose gaze turns flesh into stone.
Basilisk: The Serpent King is a action, horror, tv
movie film directed by Stephen Furst.
Two millennia ago, a Lybian king has a basilisk (snake-shaped dragon), which petrifies
people, subjected to the same fate with a golden scepter during a solar eclipse.
Both these and several victims are dug up by modern
archaeologist Harrison 'Harry' McColl's expedition.
Despite a cryptic warning from tribal locals, everything
goes to his Colorado university's museum.
It's all exhibited during another eclipse, which leads to the monster reviving.
Harry and some of his friends must try to petrify the monster again.
Dr. Harrison 'Harry' McColl, played by Jeremy London.
Rachel Donegal, played by Wendy Carter.
Col. Douglas, played by Cleavant Derricks.
Rudy Skeeters, played by Griff Furst.
Sierra, played by Sarah Skeeters.
Carlton, played by Stephen Furst.
Serpents (Hebrew: נָחָשׁ, romanized: nāḥāš) are referred to in
both the Hebrew Bible and the New Testament.
The symbol of a serpent or snake played important roles in the religious traditions
and cultural life of ancient Greece, Egypt, Mesopotamia, and Canaan.
The serpent was a symbol of evil power and chaos from the underworld as
well as a symbol of fertility, life, healing, and rebirth.
Nāḥāš (נחש‎), Hebrew for "snake", is also associated with divination, including
the verb form meaning "to practice divination or fortune-telling".
Nāḥāš occurs in the Torah to identify the serpent in the Garden of Eden.
Throughout the Hebrew Bible, it is also used in conjunction with
seraph to describe vicious serpents in the wilderness.
The tannin, a dragon monster, also occurs throughout the Hebrew Bible.
In the Book of Exodus, the staves of Moses and Aaron are turned
into serpents, a nāḥāš for Moses, a tannin for Aaron.
In the New Testament, the Book of Revelation makes use of ancient serpent and the Dragon
several times to identify Satan or the Devil (Revelation 12:9; 20:2).
The serpent is most often identified with the
hubristic Satan, and sometimes with Lilith.
The narrative of the Garden of Eden and the fall of humankind constitute a mythological tradition shared by all the Abrahamic religions, with a presentation more or less symbolic of
Abrahamic morals and religious beliefs, which had an overwhelming impact on human sexuality, gender roles, and sex differences both in the Western and Islamic civilizations.
In mainstream (Nicene) Christianity, the doctrine of the Fall is
closely related to that of original sin or ancestral sin.
Unlike Christianity, the other major Abrahamic religions, Judaism and Islam, do not have a concept of
"original sin", and instead have developed varying other interpretations of the Eden narrative.
The tone is dark.